<Language xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Code>EN</Code>
  <HelpPage>
    <StationpediaPage>
      <Key>StationpediaExtensionPage</Key>
      <Title>Stationpedia Extension</Title>
      <Text>You are playing with the JonasVerzockt expansion! Thanks a lot!
Here you can find some info, hints and etc.! Did you find a bug or a wish to add something?
Write me an e-mail! Yes I have something like that ;)! {LINK:Dummy;mail@jonasverzockt.de}

{HEADER:INFOS}
In the extension we may have hidden some insiders for Konny87! Who has seen them and wondered now knows ;)!
How can you find Konny87 you ask? I will gladly tell you how!
Discord: {LINK:Dummy;PrdGfX4haq}
Twitch: {LINK:Dummy;konny87}
YouTube: {LINK:Dummy;@Konny87}

So who is this Konny87? Well he introduces himself under Twitch like this:
"Hello and welcome! I'm Konny87 and I play a lot of Oxygen not Included here. I try to make the game interesting for everyone, no matter if newbie or veteran. Other than that I like to play multiplayer, puzzle, survival, action-adventure and base building games."

{HEADER:NOTES}
ATTENTION! THIS IS CURRENTLY STILL A BETA AND HEAVILY UNDER DEVELOPMENT! MY NATIVE LANGUAGE IS NOT ENGLISH! SORRY FOR POSSIBLE GAMATICAL ERRORS!

{HEADER:NEW PAGES}
{LINK:SmeltingPage1;Melting}
{LINK:SmeltingPage2;Basics of metal processing}
{LINK:SmeltingPage3;General metal processing}
{LINK:SmeltingPage4;Advanced metal processing}
{LINK:MiningPage;Mining}
{LINK:AdvancedMiningPage;Advanced mining}
{LINK:MiningStrategy;Mining strategy}
{LINK:CombustionGases;Combustion gases}

Are also under guides!</Text>
      <DisplayFilter>Lore</DisplayFilter>
    </StationpediaPage>
    <StationpediaPage>
      <Key>SmeltingPage1</Key>
      <Title>Melting</Title>
      <Text>Since we couldn't send along everything you need, and the current delivery services will only end up with you if you can pay them, you'll have to build your stuff yourself first. As already described in mining, we have sent you one or the other "liberated" building plan. So all you have to do is gather the stuff around you and refine it. So turn ore into metal and alloys. So once you have the appropriate{LINK:OrePage;Ores}, you need to turn it into {LINK:IngotPage;Ingots} so you can use their {LINK:ReagentPage;Reagents}. Easier said than done. We've sent you along a {THING:StructureArcFurnace}. This will handle the simple metals and only requires a little power. But you will quickly realize that it won't be enough for more complicated {LINK:AlloyPage;Alloys} and eventually for very complicated {LINK:SuperAlloyPage;Alloys}. For that you need the {THING:StructureFurnace} and then even more so the one in the {THING:StructureAdvancedFurnace}. So ideally you need to collect and filter ice. If the atmosphere doesn't allow that... phew! I hope you've been paying attention in chemistry, the individual ores should be able to produce some gas. Best look it up, we'll put those properties in your manual!
For the complex alloys you need to achieve mixtures with perfect ratios, {LINK:TemperaturePage;temperature}, and {LINK:PressurePage;pressure}. We have also written these values in the manual. But now we come to the topics that build on each other. We will not be able to explain everything here. Budget is already not intended for this, this is just my lunch break, in which I write you this!
{LINK:SmeltingPage2;Basics of metal processing}</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
    </StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
      <Key>SmeltingPage2</Key>
      <Title>Basics of metal processing</Title>
      <Text>The first oven was built by us from parts of the management kitchen. Unfortunately, the hardware has been more for pizzas and the like. So you'll need some time melting.
Build the {THING:StructureArcFurnace} so that it can be connected to the power grid. You've already connected the solar power or built the coal combustion, right? If not... do you think this thing runs on fairy dust? Stop reading and worry about the power supply!
Then, when you've done all that, just throw in the ore you want and turn it on. After what feels like an eternity, the ingots will tumble out the back. Quickly assemble everything you need. But don't dwell on this furnace. The throughput is low. It was simply a stopgap measure.
Look to work your way to the {THING:StructureFurnace} as quickly as possible.  The plan has been sent along. 
This also has more volume and can support initial alloys. But more on that in the next chapter when you're finally ready!
{LINK:SmeltingPage3;General metal processing}</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
    </StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
      <Key>SmeltingPage3</Key>
      <Title>General metal processing</Title>
      <Text>Ok, so you have built the {THING:StructureFurnace}. This one works differently. In addition to a power supply, you now also have to work with gas! But you can now process large quantities and different ores at the same time. But be careful! There can be serious problems here. Remember your fire safety training or explosive materials training? No? Oh.... oh right, there was that budget issue again. Well, you'll find out what can happen in the worst case scenario. Maybe don't build the smelter and gas processing next to each other or in the middle of your base! You have to keep certain temperatures, pressures and quantities for the alloys, after all. For that, check out the manual pages we prepared. 
So how exactly does it work? Well, you have set up the {THING:StructureFurnace} and connected the gas inlet and outlet? Perfect. Ideally, you also think about emergency measures e.g. to quickly vent or cool the furnace. Well-meant tip!
Otherwise, you throw in the appropriate quantities at the appropriate temperature and wait briefly. Examples? Steel. 150g iron ore and 50g coal into the furnace. Is a gracious product to start with - you just need to get above 900°K with the temperature. For that, it's enough to throw hydrogen with oxygen into the furnace. Oh... yeah, ok, you can actually physically throw it in including the impurities .... but better not get used to it for too long. It increases the risk in operation. Throw in 2 ice chunks of hydrogen and 1 ice chunk of oxygen in proportion. Ideally, you do this in an environment where it's not already melting in your hands. And don't do too much at once! Wait to see how the pressure behaves in the furnace. If you throw too much in at once, the oven could rapidly change state!
After you use it, though, you should think about what you're doing with the gas in the melt. The temperature, etc. can still help you with other issues. Be creative! Or just vent it to the atmosphere via a vent. We'll probably give you other manual pages, for example, on process gases. That is, if we don't need the lunch breaks for more pressing fixes.
Now that you can produce the basic alloys yourself, you can build a {THING:StructureAdvancedFurnace}. This is where you will tackle the next alloys, which have even smaller frameworks.
But more about that in advanced metal processing.
{LINK:SmeltingPage4;Advanced metal processing}</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
    </StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
      <Key>SmeltingPage4</Key>
      <Title>Advanced metal processing</Title>
      <Text>You really came this far? And you haven't blown yourself up yet? Excellent! And let someone say again that the first candidate who is in the budget and in position 2638729 in the selection process is not good enough!
But good. You know how it works with heating up the oven and also where to find the individual recipes. Perfect! Hopefully you had already worked out a gas infrastructure and are no longer throwing individual chunks of ice into the oven. 
So we can keep everything relatively short here. Lunch break, and I still have to sew your suit. So as taught in the previous course:
Set up oven.
Fill with gas.
Slowly pour in the raw materials of the recipe. Be aware of the gases from the ores. If you fill in too many raw materials, i.e. kilograms, extreme conditions can arise! So check beforehand which gases will be released.
And now you will notice with the {LINK:SuperAlloyPage;Alloys} that the conditions become really exhausting. Think carefully about what you do. Temperature control is of course possible with the well known hydrogen/oxygen mixture. Or hydrogen and nitrous oxide in a 1:1 ratio - but the handling was still extremely experimental. You have to find that out for yourself.
You want to increase the pressure? Hopefully you've secured old gas that was still relatively warm. 
Or you want to cool? Depending on where we sent you, you can put cold CO2 or N2 into the furnace.
Be creative in solving your problems. We can't send you a larger guide at this time, unfortunately. The vendors of the {THING:StructureAdvancedFurnace} wouldn't let us experiment with the demonstration model any longer. Something had made them nervous after such strange creaking occurred....

Anyway - good luck. If you still have questions, just send them to us via Herm er a transport company of your choice. We will answer you in 6-12 months. Alternatively look here from time to time, we try to write a more detailed tutorial for advanced metalworking!</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
    </StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
      <Key>MiningPage</Key>
      <Title>Mining</Title>
      <Text>You can mine {LINK:OrePage;Dirty Ore} with a {THING:ItemMiningDrill} to start. If you carry a {THING:ItemMiningBelt} or later {THING:ItemMiningBackPack}, the {LINK:OrePage;Dirty Ore} will be placed in it automatically.
You can also use some other stuff. We've sent you some more stuff along as blueprints. More on that in the mining strategy we came up with. But first, what kind of stuff was for mining in the first place.Don't worry, just the terms so you've heard of it. What the parts can do, had to find out later or look for it in the last documents. We are still gathering all the information ourselves.
With increasing progress you will get new possibilities. At first you can use a better, faster {THING:ItemMiningDrill}. Additionally, you can rely on the {THING:ItemSensorLenses} to find the material of your choice near you at any time. You'll figure out how it all works. After that, there are various options to automate ore extraction. 
{THING:StructureAutoMinerSmall} 
{THING:StructureHorizontalAutoMiner} 
{THING:Robot} 
{THING:StructureToolManufactory}
These structures all have different advantages as well as disadvantages. 
Short descriptions without major spoilers about it {LINK:AdvancedMiningPage;AdvancedMining}. 
For more options, see {LINK:AutomatedRocketPage;RocketTheme}. However, these have the highest requirements, but provide raw materials on some celestial bodies that may not be extractable in any other way.</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
	</StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
      <Key>AdvancedMiningPage</Key>
      <Title>Advanced mining</Title>
      <Text>{THING:StructureAutoMinerSmall} Simple mining structure. A drill head is propelled horizontally, mining everything within its reach. Limited mining amount.
   
{THING:StructureHorizontalAutoMiner} Simple mining structure. A drill head is advanced vertically until it reaches bedrock. Everything in its path is mined. Limited amount of mining.
   
{THING:Robot} Small robot that, with proper programming, can drive itself across the surface and mine ore. Beware - storms damage its health and can destroy it if not maintained.
   
{THING:StructureToolManufactory} Advanced Mining Structure. Drills through the earth until it reaches bedrock. Only when this is reached does it begin mining for raw materials. This {THING:ItemDirtyOre} must be further processed before it can be used.
{LINK:MiningStrategy;Mining strategy}</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
	</StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
	<Key>MiningStrategy</Key>
    <Title>Mining strategy</Title>
	<Text>Now that we've soberly told you what the options are in the previous articles on mining, let's move on to what you should definitely do. We couldn't tell you this on Earth, unfortunately - lawyers, copyright and such... you know the scourge of mankind. Unfortunately, for budget reasons, mining drill had to be your primary tool. Be glad, we collected privately here to acquire it. The space agency said the pickaxe would do as well. As I'm sure you've noticed by now, the cheapest bidder won here. Unfortunately, we couldn't really test what it was really capable of. We were allowed to steal er test the plans for better hardware from better providers, but unfortunately we can't reproduce them on Earth for copyright reasons. Did I already mention the lawyers?
What does this mean now? If the inclined astronaut has built the basic things for his survival, i.e. the other budget topic, and no longer has to search for resources in a panic every 5 minutes, he can simplify the situation considerably.
From here on, you should ONLY read on the side if you don't want to figure it out on your own.  If you think "Hey, you 2749 scientists may be able to shoot me here, but I'll take it from here" - go ahead. Maybe you had "The Martian" with you as a book for boredom and all. 
Anyway: 

{HEADER:SPOILER}
The first step should be to produce an improved Mining Drill in the {THING:StructureToolManufactory}. This will allow you to mill through the ground much faster.
With it, common resources can be excavated quickly and profitably. 
Right after that, you can almost start using automatic mining methods.
Let's be honest - we have copied some options from the suppliers, but only a few options are worthwhile.
Autominer? OGRE? AIMEe? Yes, AIMEe is a nice partner for lonely moments. Everyone should have an AIMEe in their base that smiles at them when you swap their battery. To mine ores with it, the little one is much too bad - and not really long lasting. The Autominer and OGRE? Forget them.
The {THING:StructureDeepMiner} is the ultimate early target. It directly accesses planetary resources and mines oodles of them compared to the other buildings.
You, dear astronaut, should use this building for all resources away from the ice.
Dig down to the bedrock and create a small cave. In this cave you place the {THING:StructureDeepMiner} on the ground. This way the path for its drill heads is relatively short.
However, it does not extract pure raw materials yet, but dirt. This has to be processed in one of the centrifuges.
"Oh" you will think to yourself right now - yes exactly. The disadvantage of these buildings is the increased power consumption and gas consumption for the miner and the centrifuges. But you can usually find coal in the dirty ore. Otherwise there should be enough raw materials to build wind turbines and solar panels in mass. 
Why do you keep reading here? Go! Go mine raw materials.
Oh... you're still missing some special ones? Yes. Grab your {THING:ItemSensorLenses} and plunge through the rocks. This thing scans across the earth and shows you all the resource locations. Searching has never been so much fun. But don't forget to install the chip for it. Without the chip you'll have to steal the mushrooms from Konny87... that is, the secret stash... we would never have heard of.... . With it you see then perhaps also appropriate patterns - whether behind it however also ore is?

So... still need ice? {LINK:AutomatedRocketPage;AutomatedRocket} helps for the ice production. But be careful, Vulcan and Venus need more work again, so that the stuff doesn't evaporate when you land or the rocket bursts directly.... Well. You'll have to think of solutions. We haven't thought of any yet,...... write us if you have a solution... and survive long enough!</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
	</StationpediaPage>
	<StationpediaPage>
      <Key>CombustionGases</Key>
      <Title>Combustion gases</Title>
      <Text>{HEADER:There are generally 2 fuel gases!}

{GAS:Volatiles} + {GAS:Oxygen}
Mixture 2:1 (2 moles H2 + 1 mole O2 = 3 moles Pol + 6 moles CO2).
Gases triple! Temperature at perfect combustion is 2500° (Hotter environments cool down as a result!).
Spontaneous ignition at 300°C

{GAS:Volatiles} + {GAS:NitrousOxide}
Mixture 1:1 (1 mole N2O + 1 mole H2 = 2 moles N2 + 2 moles CO2).
Gases double! Temperature at perfect combustion 6000° (Hotter environments cool down because of this!)
Spontaneous ignition at 50°C

{HEADER:General}
At least 1 mole per fuel gas is required for combustion. Regardless of the ignition temperature, sparks can ignite the mixture at any time! If a part of the fuel gases is liquid, these burn only if the liquid evaporates! The combustion takes place linear and always burns about 15% of the fuel gas per tick!

{HEADER:Impure mixtures during burning processes}
If there is N2 and O2 in the gases during the burning process, a small amount of N2O is produced! N2 Inhibits the temperature rise clearly!
Pole is a very good filling gas if it has the right temperature to keep the heat of the combustion for a long time (e.g. in the melt)!</Text>
    <DisplayFilter>Guides</DisplayFilter>
	</StationpediaPage>
  </HelpPage>
</Language>